<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hydrology on Yu-Fen Huang</title>
    <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/tags/hydrology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hydrology on Yu-Fen Huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 09:58:20 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yfhuang7.github.io/tags/hydrology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>23 Unsolved Hydrology Problems</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/23-unsolved-hydrology-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 09:58:20 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/23-unsolved-hydrology-questions/</guid>
      <description>Once a while, hydrologist gathered and discussed what the important hydrology questions that are not solved yet. Recently, Blöschl et al. (2019) spent more than a year to survey and conclude 23 unsolved hydrology problems. I really appreciate their work - it&amp;rsquo;s always to know where we are, what the status is, and what our goals are in the community. The problems have been classified into 6 groups - &amp;ldquo;The variability and change&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Space variability and scaling&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Variability of extreme&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Interfaces in hydrology&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Measurements and data&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Modeling methods&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Interfaces with society&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Current Project] Characterizing natural flow regime of Hawaiian forest watersheds and its implication on downstream water availability</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-mcintire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 12:06:42 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-mcintire/</guid>
      <description>PI: Dr. Yinphan Tsang
This project proposes to strategically characterize the natural flow regime of forest watersheds, the water resources protected by Hawai&amp;rsquo;i natural forests. This project proposes to support and train students and research assistants to perform various hydrological analyses to understand and reconstruct the natural flow regime of forested watersheds. The objectives of this study include:
 Examine types of forest watersheds and their typical streamflow response to precipitation, and describe their natural flow regime When data available, perform hydrologic analyses and/or modeling to address or simulate stream flow dynamics of the forest watersheds  This project will gather preliminary data and ultimately applying to large federal agency proposals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Current Project] Characterizing the water availability and nutrient transport of Hawaii’s watersheds and its implication to downstream agriculture and coastal environment</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-hatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 12:06:42 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-hatch/</guid>
      <description>PI: Dr. Yinphan Tsang
This project proposes to characterize the water availability and quality of watersheds in Hawaii. This project proposes to support and train students and research assistants to survey the water quality and quantity and to perform hydrologic analyses. The objectives of this study include:
 Research and document the current status of water availability and nutrient loading in watersheds of Hawaii. Describe the nutrient loading, transport, and nutrient dynamic in Hawaii’s watersheds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Current Project] Deriving a sub-daily gridded rainfall dataset by combining rain gauge networks and weather radar in Hawaiʻi</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-radarqpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 12:06:42 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-radarqpe/</guid>
      <description>(This is the second topic of my Ph.D. dissertation.)
Current status: Concluded that the NEXRAD LEVEL III rainfall data won&amp;rsquo;e be included, and now testing different merging methods.
Goals This study seeks a high spatial- and temporal-resolution of rainfall data that can be applied to research of extreme rainfall and streamflow events. Four steps are listed to achieve the goal: 1) collect data, select events and evaluate the rainfall product for Oʻahu; 2) compare existed merging methods with the selected events; 3) adjust the method based on local characteristics; 4) develop a framework and extend to the longer period (2014 – 2018) and maybe other islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Current Project] Shifting magnitude and seasonality of streamflow extremes and the relationship with rainfall across the Hawaiian Islands</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-peakflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 12:06:42 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-peakflow/</guid>
      <description>(This is the first topic of my Ph.D. dissertation.)
Current status: Manuscript in prep. as first author (plan to submit in 2020)
Abstract Flooding is a significant threat to life and property in Hawaiʻi. As climate warming continues to alter precipitation patterns and hydrological processes in tropics, characterizing the shifting patterns in magnitude, seasonality, and location of floods will improve our understanding of the consequences of changing climate and better prepare us for future flooding events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Current Project] Understanding the effects of different uncertainty sources on WRF-Hydro modeling on Oʻahu</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-wrfhydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 12:06:42 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/projects/project-wrfhydro/</guid>
      <description>(This is the third topic of my Ph.D. dissertation.)
Current status: Learning and practicing sensitivity analysis with WRF-Hydro
Goals Simulation from hydrological models are affected by the input data and model parameters. Understanding the major sources of uncertainties is critical to support model calibration, validation and uncertainty reduction. In this study, I will apply the updated sub-daily rainfall to the WRF-Hydro on Oʻahu and conduct sensitivity analysis. In addition, the sensitivity of model parameters that stand for different watershed characteristics (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>