<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hula on Yu-Fen Huang</title>
    <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/tags/hula/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hula on Yu-Fen Huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:45:52 -1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yfhuang7.github.io/tags/hula/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The expression between ancient and modern</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/expression_of_hula/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:45:52 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/expression_of_hula/</guid>
      <description>Today, in the hula class, kumu (hula instructor) answered one of my question bothering me long time while dancing hula - the expression.
Hula can be classified into two category. Hula kahiko is the older and more traditional form of hula. Hula kahiko is danced to chants in Hawaiian. The instruments can be drums, ipu (gourd), etc. The movement is more basic, and facial expressions are more ritualistic. Whereas, modern hula, hula ʻauana, is softer and melodious with modern instruments such as ukuleles and guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hula Instrument - ʻulili and ʻukēkē</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/hula-instrument/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 22:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/hula-instrument/</guid>
      <description>It was always amazing to watch Merrie Monarch. Besides hula, I can learn about Hawaiian mele (songs) and also the hula instruments. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching Merrie Monarch for 3 years, and I&amp;rsquo;m still learning about the hula instruments that I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen. In Merrie Monarch 2019, there are two interesting instruments - ʻulili and ʻukēkē.
ʻulili I thought it was some kind of ʻuliʻuli while watching TV. But kumu Noe told us that it was ʻulili.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kumu Noe I</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/kumu-noe-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 19:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/kumu-noe-1/</guid>
      <description>Before the performance, kumu hula Noe told us:
Hula is a package deal, you need to get your timing, follow the rhythm, make sure the right gesture, and be grateful and strong at the same time. Also, you need to show your personality! If you just dance the dance, it&amp;rsquo;s not hula, student.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been dancing hula in UH with kumu Noe for two years. Kumu is strict at the same time she try her best to respect her student, other halau, and other culture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
