<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>literature on Yu-Fen Huang</title>
    <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/tags/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in literature on Yu-Fen Huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 09:58:20 -1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yfhuang7.github.io/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>23 Unsolved Hydrology Problems</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/23-unsolved-hydrology-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 09:58:20 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/23-unsolved-hydrology-questions/</guid>
      <description>Once a while, hydrologist gathered and discussed what the important hydrology questions that are not solved yet. Recently, Blöschl et al. (2019) spent more than a year to survey and conclude 23 unsolved hydrology problems. I really appreciate their work - it&amp;rsquo;s always to know where we are, what the status is, and what our goals are in the community. The problems have been classified into 6 groups - &amp;ldquo;The variability and change&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Space variability and scaling&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Variability of extreme&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Interfaces in hydrology&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Measurements and data&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Modeling methods&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Interfaces with society&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodama and Barnes 1997</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/kodama-and-barnes-1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 08:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/kodama-and-barnes-1997/</guid>
      <description>Kodama and Barnes (1997) had a great literature review in flash flood and the flash flood in Hawaii from meteorological perspectives. They conducted their research on southeast Mauna Loa from 1978 through 1992. By looking into synoptic influences, rainfall patterns, stability indices, precipitable water, upslope component of the surface winds, midlevel moisture, they found:
rain mainly occur over the volcano slopes facing the low-level flow; the heaviest rainfall usually occurs upslope above the 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If precipitation extremes are increasing, why aren&#39;t floods?</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/sharma-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/sharma-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description>I appreciate all the efforts that has been done for the previous research. Some papers provide us knowledge; some papers correct our imagination of the world; some papers gave a clear picture of how the world processing, and some papers inspire and encourage us. Ashish&amp;rsquo;s paper is one of the inspiration, at least to me.
I met Dr. Ashish Sharma in the Asia Oceania Geosciences Society conference this year. I accidently went to his talk, and was impressed by how clear he explain a concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Escaping from a Small Watershed</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/dunne-and-black-1970/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 19:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/dunne-and-black-1970/</guid>
      <description>Well, the title of this paper is &amp;ldquo;Partial Area Contributions to Storm Runoff in a Small New England Watershed&amp;rdquo; by Dunne and Black (1970), but Dunne used a lot of &amp;ldquo;water escaping&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;water escaped&amp;rdquo; in the article. It made me laugh every time I read water escape from where to where. I hope I can escape successfully, too!
Dunne and Black created an experiment for testing the theory of Horton overland flow and subsurface flow in their 60-acre backyard in Vermont.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatialized Flash Flood Guidance (SFFG)</title>
      <link>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/sffg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yfhuang7.github.io/posts/sffg/</guid>
      <description>Douinot et al. (2016) indicate that the FFG method significantly overestimates the intensity necessary to exceed the threshold flow for high intensity events in three catchments in France. They show the importance of the rainfall spatial variability in the estimating the rainfall intensity threshold for the flash flood forecasting. They proposed a Spatialized FFG (SFFG), a modified FFG with considering rainfall spatial characteristics. It has better estimations than the FFG in the high rainfall intensity cases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
